RG 028:008, Governor's Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures, 1978
Connecticut State Library
Governor's Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures records
1976-1979
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Governor's Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures
.5 cubic feet
The Commission studied Connecticut's fiscal situation and evaluated various revenue and expenditure control devices.
RG028_008
1979-041
Historical Note
Gov. Ella T. Grasso appointed the Governor’s Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures in June 1978 to study Connecticut’s fiscal situation as well as evaluate various revenue and expenditure control devices in Connecticut. Frazar B. Wilde, Chairman of the Board Emeritus, Connecticut General Life Insurance Company, chaired the 15-member group. Dr. Ronald C. Fisher served as Executive Director.
Scope and Content
Includes correspondence to Chairman Wilde, meeting minutes, preliminary and final reports, and various reference publications.
Related Material
RG 028:001, Commission to Investigate the Advisability of Consolidating Certain State Boards and Commissions and to Investigate the Public Health Laws, 1915.
RG 028:002, Commission on the Reorganization of State Departments, 1935-1937.
RG 028:003, Commission to study the Integration of the State Judicial System, 1943-1945.
RG 028:004, Commission on State Government Organization, 1949-1950.
RG 028:005, Commission on Services and Expenditures (Etherington Commission), 1971.
RG 028:006, Committee on the Structure of State Government (Filer Committee), 1976-1977.
RG 028:007, Human Servuces Reorganization Commission, 1977-1979.
RG 028:009, Commission to Study the Management of State Government (Thomas Commission), 1989-1991.
RG 028:010, Commission to Effect Government Reorganisation (Hull-Harper Commission), 1991-1992.
Index Terms
Persons:
Fisher, Ronald C; Wilde, Frazar B
Organizations:
Connecticut. Governor's Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures
Subjects:
Connecticut -- Appropriations and expenditures; Connecticut. Governor's Study Group on Limitation of Government Expenditures -- Records and correspondence; Expenditures, Public; Finance, Public -- Connecticut; Government spending policy -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Press releases; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
Pam Diamond, Connecticut General Life Insurance Company, transferred the records to the State Archives on March 29, 1979.
Container List
- Records, 1976-1979
  - Correspondence to Frazer Wilde, 1978 June-November; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Copies only. Includes letter from Gov. Grasso thanking Mr. Wilde for accepting the chair. Also letters and attachments from the Office of Policy and Management, Connecticut Conference on Municipalities, and Connecitcut Public Expenditure Council.
  - 2. Minutes, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - 3. Approved Scope of Study, 1978 July 19; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Alternative preliminary study group positions.
  - 4. Press releases, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Dr. Ronald C. Fisher's appointment as Executive Director, October 10, 1978; report presentation to Gov. Grasso, March 8, 1979.
  - 5. Preliminary reports, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    First written report, November 10, 1978 presenting fiscal situation overview; third written report, December 8, 1979 presents fiscal control options for the state.
  - 6. Final report, 1979 March (Box 1)
    Report of the Governor's Study Group on the Limitation of Government Expenditures.
    56 pages.
  - 7. Reference publications, 1976-1978; 22 items (Box 1)
    - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relation. Intergovernmental Perspective 43(3) Summer Washington, D.C., 1978. (Box 1)
    - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relation. "Part 3 Expenditures." In Significant Features of Fiscal Federalism. 1976-77 ed. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 1977. (Box 1)
    - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relation. State Limitations on Local Taxes Expenditures. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, February 1977. (Box 1)
    - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relation. State Mandating of Local Expenditures. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, July 1978. (Box 1)
    - Barone, Michael. "What the Voters Were Saying." Wall Street Journal. 22 November 1978. (Box 1)
    - Bell, Michael and Ronald C. Fisher State Limitations on Local Taxing and Spending Powers: Comment and Re-Evaluation. August 1978. (Box 1)
    - Colorado. General Statutes, "Restruction on State Spending". 27-75-201.1. (Box 1)
    - Colorado. Petition for referendum. State Expenditure Limit. Defeated November 1978. (Box 1)
    - Congressional Research Service. Proposition 13: An Economic Analysis. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 15 June 1978. (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Governor's Urban Action Task Force. "Discussion Draft: Committee Reports." Hartford, Conn.: OPM, 12 October 1978. (Box 1)
    - Conneecticut Conference of Municipalities. A Profile of Austerity: Hard Times Push Connecticut Towns and Cities into Far Reaching Economy Moves. New Haven, Conn.: March 1976. (Box 1)
    - Conneecticut Conference of Municipalities. Some Materials Concerning Expenditure and Tax Limitations in Connecticut. New Haven, Conn.: September 1978. (Box 1)
    - Conneecticut Conference of Municipalities. State Mandates to Cities and Towns. New Haven, Conn.: March 1976. (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Public Expenditure Council, Inc. Connecticut State Revenues, Expenditures, Employees from 1950. Data Series. Hartford, Conn.: Travelers Insurance Co., March 1976. (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Public Expenditure Council, Inc. Tax Payers News. 30 (5) September-October 1978. (Box 1)
    - Congressional Research Service. Proposition 13: An Economic Analysis. Washington, D.C.: Government Printing Office, 15 June 1978. (Box 1)
    - Jacobs, Sanford L. "Capping New Jersey's Taxes." Wall Street Journal. 31 October 1978. (Box 1)
    - Michigan Initiative Amendemnt [to the State Constitution]. "Local Revenue Limit." November 1978. (Box 1)
    - Petersen, John and Marcia Claxton. "Tax and Expenditure Limits: Proposition 13 and Its Alternatives." Special Bulletin 1978C. Municipal Finance Officers' Association 1978. (Box 1)
    - "Tax Revolt Heads for Fall Ballots" State Government News. July 1978. (Box 1)
    - Tennessee. Constitutional Amendment. "State Revenue Limit." March 1978. (Box 1)
    - Trend Report. "An Update on the 'Taxpayers' Revolt'." Unpublished memo to subsscribers. 2 Auagust 1978. (Box 1)